<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: updates | Phil 540]]></title>
  <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/categories/updates/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-29T19:03:27-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alejandro Pérez Carballo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/04/29/final-paper/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T18:46:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/04/29/final-paper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are enrolled in the seminar for credit, you must submit a final paper. Papers are due on <strong>Monday May 13, 2013</strong>, by email. If at all possible, please send your papers in PDF format.</p>

<p>Tomorrow is the last day I will be holding regular office hours. That said, if you want to talk to me about your paper, simply <a href="mailto:aperezca@usc.edu">email me</a> so we can set up a time to meet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Following up]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/04/23/following-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T20:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/04/23/following-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some of you asked for some references on the issues we discussed at the end of class today. Here they are, in alphabetical order:</p>

<ul>
<li>E. Anderson's <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayAbstract?fromPage=online&amp;aid=74339">contribution</a> to a symposium on Amartya Sen's philosophy.</li>
<li>C. Bicchieri, <a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/2381782">'Norms of cooperation'</a>.</li>
<li>M. Gilbert, <a href="http://pos.sagepub.com/content/36/1/3.short">'Rationality in Collective Action'</a>.</li>
<li>S. Nichols, <a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/341051">'On The Genealogy Of Norms: A Case For The Role Of Emotion In Cultural Evolution'</a>.</li>
<li>A. Rosenberg, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/yjk0eeybxsn19qi/Rosenberg.pdf">'Darwinism in moral philosophy and social theory'</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Also worth checking out, although I can't give you an electronic version of them, are:</p>

<ul>
<li>R. Frank,  'Cooperation through emotional commitment', in R. Nesse, et al., <em>The Evolution of Commitment</em>, pp. 57–76.</li>
<li>Skyrms, <em>The Evolution of the Social Contract</em>.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Additional references]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/04/02/additional-references/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-02T15:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/04/02/additional-references</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those of you who are interested in Railton's account of desire, it might be worth taking a look at his <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/kc4zvxr2pykx6nq/Railton2012.pdf">Presidential Address</a> (Central Division) of 2012.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/10/updates/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T11:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/10/updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few things:</p>

<ul>
<li>I have updated the <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/readings/">reading schedule</a> for the rest of the semester. Please <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/readings/">take a look</a>, especially if you will be giving an in-class presentation (you will notice it differs a fair bit from the tentative schedule on the syllabus).</li>
<li>A final reminder to those of you taking this class for credit: you need to submit <em>three short response pieces</em> before the end of the semester. If you are writing on something we are reading for a given Tuesday, your response piece is due on the previous Sunday.</li>
<li>Also for those of you taking this class for credit: you should be thinking about scheduling a meeting with me to discuss your final paper. On the syllabus it is stated that this meeting should take place before March 31st. Since I had miscalculated when Spring break was going to be, I have decided to move that date forward until April 2.</li>
</ul>


<p>Let me know if you have any questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presentation schedule]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/01/presentation-schedule/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T17:56:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/01/presentation-schedule</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The presentation schedule is now available on <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/calendar/">the course calendar</a>. Please let me know if you have any concerns about the date you were assigned. If you are taking this seminar for credit, but are not on the seminar calendar, please contact me as soon as possible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
