<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: syllabus | Phil 540]]></title>
  <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/categories/syllabus/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-11T13:09:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alejandro Pérez Carballo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/10/updates/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T11:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/10/updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few things:</p>

<ul>
<li>I have updated the <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/readings/">reading schedule</a> for the rest of the semester. Please <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/readings/">take a look</a>, especially if you will be giving an in-class presentation (you will notice it differs a fair bit from the tentative schedule on the syllabus).</li>
<li>A final reminder to those of you taking this class for credit: you need to submit <em>three short response pieces</em> before the end of the semester. If you are writing on something we are reading for a given Tuesday, your response piece is due on the previous Sunday.</li>
<li>Also for those of you taking this class for credit: you should be thinking about scheduling a meeting with me to discuss your final paper. On the syllabus it is stated that this meeting should take place before March 31st. Since I had miscalculated when Spring break was going to be, I have decided to move that date forward until April 2.</li>
</ul>


<p>Let me know if you have any questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readings for next week]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/01/readings-for-next-week/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T17:45:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/03/01/readings-for-next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The readings for next week are now listed <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/readings/">here</a>.</p>

<p>I have updated the schedule until the first meeting after Spring Break. I will post the rest of the reading schedule shortly.</p>

<p>If you are presenting on any given date, you are free to focus on one of the assigned readings, or a part thereof. But make sure to let me know in advance what you will be presenting on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next week]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/02/21/next-week/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-21T08:28:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/02/21/next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The readings for next week are now listed <a href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil540/readings/">here</a>.</p>

<p>I will update the reading schedule shortly, once I get a better sense of when our second make up session will be. If you are concerned about what material you will present on, in light of the date you signed up for, please let me know.</p>

<p>Finally, for those of you who are taking the seminar for credit, remember that you need to write <em>three response pieces</em>, and that you need to schedule a meeting to talk to me about your seminar paper by March 31st.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preview]]></title>
    <link href="http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/01/03/preview/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T20:56:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://apc.github.com/phil540/blog/2013/01/03/preview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm still working on the syllabus for the course. But I thought it would be good to give an idea of what the seminar will be about. So here is a blurb of sorts.</p>

<p>Beliefs seem to have, as part of their job description, the carrying of information about the world around us. Perhaps this can help explain why beliefs can be rational or irrational: rationality gets its purchase on beliefs because it is a reasonable guide to the facts that beliefs are meant to track. It makes sense to talk of a rational change in belief, say, because we are confronted with <em>evidence</em> that pulls in one direction or another. But there are many other attitudes, in particular <em>conative</em> and <em>affective</em> attitudes (<em>non-cognitive</em> attitudes, for short), whose role seems to have little to do with tracking features of the environment. Does this mean that there can be no substantive rationality constraints on non-cognitive attitudes? If there are, what is their source? Is there such a thing as a rational change in non-cognitive attitudes?</p>

<p>The first and second parts of the seminar will revolve around the question of whether and how rationality constraints conative and affective attitudes. The final part of the seminar will be focused on the question of whether and how non-cognitivists views in meta-ethics can account for the ways in which moral thought is rationally constrained.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
